Profile

James Fultz

Technical Support | Technical Writer

https://jamesfultz.github.io/JamesFultz/ www.linkedin.com/in/James-Fultz James.Fultz@outlook.com Foley, AL 36535 (251) 223 0151

Military diesel mechanic, marine technician and field IT / access control background. I am a skilled technical writer that has a lot of field experience. Instruction guides and user manuals are my favored forms of documentation. As a technician for most of my professional career I have relied heavily on technical writing to assist in completing projects. Having 20+ years of field experience with a variety of equipment and manufactures has given me insight on what makes for good technical writing. My hobbies are building Arduino projects and repurposing PCs / Laptops with various Linux distros. I truly enjoy learning and instructing about technology.

Education

2018 to 2020 Bachelors of Science in Information Technology National University - La Jolla, CA 2011 to 2012 Technical Certification from UTI Marine Mechanics Institute - Orlando, FL 2010 to 2011 Associates of Arts in Liberal Arts and Sciences Pensacola State College - Pensacola, FL 1998 to 2001 H.S. Diploma in General Studies Mountlake Terrace High School - Mountlake Terrace, WA

Certifications and Achievements

2002 Logistics Operations School (USMC): Automotive Organizational Maintenance Course

Logistics Vehicle System Maintenance Course

2002 Oshkosh Truck Corporation: MTVR Net Maintenance Training

2007 Windward Community College:

Certificate of Appreciation Service Learning Mentorship

2015 Yamaha Marine:

Yamaha Diagnostics Interface System (YDIS)

Electrical Systems

2015 Mercury Marine:

Outboard Ignition Systems (CDM)

Verado Maintenance Electrical Systems I & II 2018 Mercury Marine:

Marine Technician Fundamentals (All Modules and Exams)

SmartCraft

Fuel Systems I & II M-TEK Cooling Systems V6 FourStroke Systems CDS-G3 Diagnostic Software

2019 Suzuki Marine:

Suzuki ServicePro Rigging

Suzuki ServicePro Electronics, SDS & Troubleshooting

Suzuki ServicePRO Mechanical

2019 Garmin:

Authorized Installer Certificate of Completion

2019 SeaStar Optimus 360 Joystick Steering (Dometic)

Certified installer / programmer

2020 Yamaha Marine:

Inline Systems

2020 Volvo Penta:

CanBUS Programming

Diagnostics

2021 EPA HVAC:

Type I & III

2023 ABYC

Electrical Certification

Employment History

Technical Support Specialist

Navico Group - Remote

2022 to Present

- Configuring and programming new installs / upgrades.
- · Customer service skills via phone and emails.
- Electrical AC & DC (high and low voltage) troubleshooting.
- · Remote support for end users and technicians.
- Technical writing to create custom documents.

Maintenance Engineer

PCH Hotels and Resorts - Point Clear, AL 2021 to 2022

- On call, immediate response for guest issues.
- Troubleshooting and customer service skills.
- Electrical and (high and low voltage) repair / replacement.
- Technical support for customers on property.

Field Service Technician

Roberts Heating and Air Conditioning - Gulf Shores, AL 2020 to 2021

- Communicate with customers about service and inspection.
- Install and perform service on equipment in the field.
- Document work orders and quotes for labor and equipment.
- Troubleshoot and repair equipment in a field environment.
- Diagnose and repair company equipment and fleet vehicles.

Service Technician

Paradise Marine Service Center - Gulf Shores, AL 2017 to 2020

- Diagnose problems in engine and vessel systems.
- Document work performed for billing and company records.
- Installation and service of large electronics packages.
- Open, update and Q.C. work orders in the database.
- · Accurately keep track of hours and parts on tickets.
- Travel technician duties (road mechanic experience).

Marine Electrician

Silver Ships Inc - Theodore, AL 2014 to 2017

- Wire and install complex electrical panels and systems.
- Worked directly with engineers in house and from industry.
- Install and calibrate electrical systems on vessels.
- Fabrication of mounting structures and storage for equipment.
- Document and present alternative options with design issues.

Service Technician

Ocean Marine Group Inc - Ocean Springs, MS 2012 to 2014

- Outfitted new vessels with electronics and engines.
- · Factory training from OEMs.
- Troubleshooting and technical support experience.
- · Networking and structured cabling.
- · Can-Bus programming and integration.

Access Control Technician

Rife Integrated Systems - Columbus, OH 2007 to 2009

- On call, travel to customer sites for troubleshooting.
- Draw prints using AutoCAD for electrical schematics.
- Run and terminate cable for CCTV and access control.
- Install and configure network IP cameras via CLI.
- Technical support experience with client IT technicians.

IT Field Technician

Windward Technical Solutions LLC - Honolulu, HI 2005 to 2007

- Build office machines and set up networks for local businesses.
- Install and update OS on PCs and servers (Windows).
- Worked in B2B data centers.
- Troubleshooting and structured cable experience.
- Install server racks and network switches.
- Experience with POTS (telephone systems).

Heavy Equipment Diesel Technician

United States Marine Corps - MCBH Kaneohe Bay, HI 2001 to 2005

- Foundations of mechanical knowledge and electrical systems.
- · Worked in 2nd and 3rd maintenance echelons.
- Troubleshooting and preventive maintenance.
- Highest award was a Navy Unit Commendation for our role in preparing and outfitting equipment for deployments in Iraq and Afghanistan.